# Scott Silverman

scottsil@mac.com

@scottsil

www.scottsil.com

408.891.2731

### Summary

I'm a technical, design-focused product guy with a passion for delightful user experiences. As a 2011 Code for America Fellow, I coordinated a development team that built 6 web apps for the City of Boston. I've also held product internships with Apple, The New York Times, and Arnold Worldwide.

#### Skills

Web Development | HTML + CSS, SASS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Ruby on Rails, Ruby, Git Design | UI, icon, logo, and print; Adobe CS5 Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks, InDesign User Experience | Rapid prototyping; Balsamiq Mockups; UX training with IDEO & Cooper Design Video & Photo | Apple Final Cut Studio; professional video production and photography

## Work Experience

Code for America | Fellow

January 2011 - January 2012

- One-year fellowship to build web products for U.S. cities and improve government operations / culture
- Lead research and development of 6 products for City of Boston & Boston Public Schools, culminating in the City recruiting a full-time agile development team, mimicking our team's structure & process
- Design and launch ClassTalk, a web app for classrooms that sent 30,000+ messages in <5 months</li>
- Pair-programming & development of Ruby on Rails web apps (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git)

Apple Inc. | Mac Specialist

June 2007 - December 2008

• Lead product & store launches; teach One to One workshops; supervise shifts and train new employees

Macworld Magazine | Senior Blog Contributor

February 2006 – May 2007

• Write 300+ posts, covering product launches, tech news and analysis for Macworld.com

## Internships

The New York Times Company | Market Research Intern

July 2010 - October 2010

Analyze data & social media to design infographics / presentations for NYT executives and sales teams

Apple Inc. | Public Relations Intern

May 2009 – August 2009

• Collaborate with product and marketing teams to pitch product to journalists & product reviewers

Arnold Worldwide | Broadcast Intern

January 2009 - May 2009

• Organize broadcast shoots and new business pitches alongside producers, casting, and creatives

Apple Inc. | Product Testing Intern

May 2008 – August 2008

• Design & run test sequences / scripts on Apple products for public marketing claims; research competition

#### Education

Tufts University, Medford, MA | B.A. 2010 – Biology, Studio Art, Communications and Media Studies

#### Awards & Honors

- Fellowship, Code for America
- Student Body Vice President, Tufts University
- Student Body Treasurer, Tufts University
- Best Documentary Film 2010, Tufts University